(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T21:53:38.620646",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
TODAY...
Chattini, let's celebrate together!
BEGINS
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of dreams
指先に絵の具の匂い
and the scent of paint on my fingertips,
湿ったキャンバスの上には
upon the damp canvas,
まだ知らない色が息をする
colors I have yet to know breathe life.
WHERE EMOTIONS BLOOM - RAORA PANTHERA BIRTHDAY LIVE 2026
Oh my, that was a good nap!
Wait, a minute... That's not my room?
W-Why am I not drawing right now?
How did I end up here?
What?
A white canvas? Huh?
What is this? Why is there a white canvas in here?
Where is my room?
Huh? Weird...
Zattino!
Ah, thank God you're here!
This place is so scary! Zattino, where are we?
Zattino? Za- Zattino!
What happened to you?!
Come here, don't worry, I got you... Ugh, you're kind of heavy though!
Don't worry, Zattino, I got you. We need to find a way out, okay?
We're gonna find a way out.
Where should we go?
Eh?! Why is there a portal now?
Did you open it? No?
Fine, I guess we should go in there.
Maybe I'm gonna wake up, maybe I'm still dreaming.
Okay, eisha! Let's go! You are kind of heavy though!
Okay, heave-ho! Let's go! You are kind of heavy though!
Eisha!
Heave-ho!
ロンリーガールはいつまでも
The lonely girl, forever and ever,
届かない夢見て
dreams of things beyond her reach,
騒ぐ頭の中を
churning around, churning around
掻き回して、掻き回して。
the noise inside her head.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
Muttering, "No problem,"
言葉は失われた？
have her words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しに終われば、
If it ends in hunting for mistakes,
また、回るの！
it's going to roll again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll keep rolling today as well,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
says the girl, says the girl,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
playing meaning into her words!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「まだですよ、まだまだ先は見えないので。
"Not yet, I still can't see what's ahead.
息を止めるの、今。」
So I'm holding my breath, right now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The ultimate fate of the rolling girl,
届かない、向こうの色
the unreachable color beyond.
重なる声と声を
Overlapping voices upon voices,
混ぜあわせて、混ぜあわせて。
blending them together, blending them together.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
Muttered, "No problem,"
言葉は失われた。
the words were lost.
どうなったって良いんだってさ
Saying it doesn't matter what happens,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
tempting her to make mistakes anyway,
誘う、坂道。
the enticing slope.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私をどうか転がして」と
"Please roll me along somehow,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
says the girl, says the girl,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
layering meaning into her silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろう」と。
"Just a little more, we should see something soon."
息を止めるの、今。
"So I'm holding my breath, right now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll keep rolling today as well,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
says the girl, says the girl,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
playing smiles into her words!
「もう良いかい？ もう良いよ。
"Are you ready yet? It's fine now.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
You must be getting tired by now, right?"
息を止めるの、今。
Stop holding your breath, right now.
今！
Now!
Ciao everyone!
Ciao tutti!
Hi, it's me, Raora Panthera from hololive English -Justice-!
Rawr! Big news!
Big stage! Oh my god, look at this!
What is this place, by the way? Why are we here?
And also, what day is it? What day is it?
Is it... is it... is it my birthday?
Thank you everyone for being here in this special day!
Thank you everyone for being here on this special day!
I'm so happy to see everyone!
Ciao ciao ciao ciao ciao! Hi everyone!
And talking about my birthday, I have a special hashtag for today...
...which is #RaoraBday2026!
So everyone make sure if you wanna share some screenshots...
...and you wanna share some comments on social media, make sure to use this hashtag!
Thank you so much!
Oh, but maybe now we should take a look at this stage!
It's so big, isn't it?
It's a little bit like... it looks like really dreamy, seems like we are in a dream.
It's a little bit like... it looks really dreamy, seems like we are in a dream.
Maybe... maybe I'm sleeping? Maybe I'm sleeping?
It's like a surrealism kind of thing.
What is this place? Where am...
Huh? My... my idol outfit?
What? Why... why am I in my idol outfit now?
Maybe that means I should sing more!
Well, might as well!
So please, listen to my songs!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to confirm it
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を
When will I be able to see
私ここでまた見ることができるの？
the future I lost from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を
I'll tear apart the overflowing shadows of anxiety
何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
as many times as it takes and keep walking in this world
とめどなく刻まれた
The time carved without end
時は今始まり告げ
is now signaling the beginning
変わらない思いをのせ
Carrying our unchanging feelings,
閉ざされた扉開けよう
let's open the closed door
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart starts running to draw the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれる
the sky is always waiting for me with its beautiful blue
だから怖くない
That's why I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't give up anymore
振り返れば仲間がいて
When I look back, my friends are there
気がつけば優しく包まれていた
Before I knew it, I was wrapped in kindness
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything was distorted,
唯一信じられるここが救いだった
this was the only place I could believe in, my salvation
喜びも悲しみも分け合えば強まる思い
If we share joy and sadness, our feelings grow stronger
この声が届くのなら
If this voice reaches you,
きっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
I'm sure we can make a miracle happen
交わした約束
I won't forget
忘れないよ
the promises we made.
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to make sure.
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward.
どんなに大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is,
越えてみせるからきっと
I'll definitely overcome it.
明日信じて
Believing in tomorrow...
祈って
...and praying.
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
Wandering in this broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
...arrived as if drawn here.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart ran forward to paint the future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stumble on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っててくれる
the sky with its beautiful blue is always waiting for me.
だから怖くない
So I'm not afraid.
もう何があっても挫けない
I won't give up no matter what happens.
ずっと
Always...
明日待って
...waiting for tomorrow.
Happy Birthday!
I'm so excited! Happy Birthday!
Thank you, Kronii! Thank you!
I'm so excited for you! It's your first 3D Birthday Live!
It is! And look at us with our idol outfits!
Our idol outfits... They're so pretty! I know, we are so gorgeous!
So cool! Ah, I'm so cool!
You are!
I am so cool! And, you know, because you're so cool...
...I want to give you a beautiful color that I think would suit you.
Me? - Yes. - Which color? Pink? Is it gonna be pink?
Is it gonna be pink? - Um, it's...
If you look at your eyes...
...your beautiful yellow eyes...
...they have curiosity and playfulness...
...and I think it suits you.
And so I would like to give this color...
...this beautiful color around us.
Which color? - Are you colorblind?
Hey! You don't have to bully me on my birthday!
You're supposed to be nice to me!
No, I mean your beautiful yellow eyes...
Ah... - It's like golden...
On my birthday, instead of giving me a gift...
...you come here, you sing and dance with me...
...and then you just start bullying me! You know what? Get out of here!
I complimented you! I complimented...
I complimented your golden... golden eyes! Isn't that beautiful?
So it's kind of like yellow, right? - Yeah, yeah!
So what does it mean? Why did you give this color to me?
Like... I just said curiosity and playfulness!
Sorry! I wasn't listening to you!
You weren't paying attention to me! You don't care about me!
My bad... You talk too much!
Sorry! I want...
Go on! Sorry...
Sorry! I want... I have a...
I think you should keep up your streak. - I have a question.
Okay! I have an answer.
Oh, yes.
Like, I was expecting like blue coming from you!
Why yellow?
Why are you making me laugh?
Is it because of the yellow?
It's... It's...
It's just...
...this, everything is so beautiful.
You're obsessed with my eyes, and...
Your eyes are so beautiful.
I was expecting more like a blue, because I thought you were like... sad.
Well, you don't have a blue color scheme in your...
Oh...
Yeah, but you... you're blue.
Yeah, it's because...
I know, I gave you blue.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah. What's that mean?
Loneliness? Sadness? Fear? Maybe?
Oh...
That's... Why would you give that to me?
Because...
I thought you liked me.
I like you!
You invited me all the way here...
...and gave me all this beautiful color, and you gave me blue?
I give you... You're so pretty like blue!
I'm so... Yeah.
And you're so pretty!
Oh, stop!
You stop!
No, you stop!
You know what? We can maybe blend blue and pink together to get...
Purple.
Ah...
Yeah.
Never mind.
What does purple mean?
What does purple mean? I don't know, we'll find out!
Oh.
Whoa, purple! You just spoiled it!
We'll find out, I guess!
I don't know!
To be continued, everyone.
To be continued, everyone! So keep watching our...
My... my... my... No, our...
That's not your birthday, it's my birthday!
It is... It is your birthday.
It is my birthday! So, keep watching, everyone.
I'm gonna keep singing and dancing for you, okay?
Woo! And be sure to use her hashtag, okay?
Yes!
Hell yeah!
#RaoraBday2026!
Ciao ciao!
Oh, also thank you Kronii for coming!
Oh yeah, you're welcome.
I forgot to thank you!
Oh yeah, thank you for having me.
Thank you for singing and dancing with me! It was so fun!
Yay!
Okay, keep up the good work!
Keep... Keep the good work!
Keep... Keep up the good work!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
And go! Ciao ciao!
Brave Shine
[Song: Brave Shine]
左手に隠した
Hidden in my left hand,
願いは願いのままで
my wishes remain just wishes.
覚めない夢見てた
I dreamed an endless dream.
右手には空の記憶
In my right hand are empty memories.
誰も知らない世界の果て
At the edge of a world known to no one,
止まない雨に打たれていた
I was struck by the never-ending rain.
守りたいものを
The strength to protect...
守れる強さ
...what I want to protect,
それを信じられなくなる弱さ
and the weakness of losing faith in it.
すべてを受け入れて
Accepting everything,
明日を探す
I search for tomorrow.
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
if I reach out my hand, there's still...
Stay the night
傷だらけの夜 You saved my life
On a night full of scars, you saved my life.
かざした刃の先に
At the tip of the raised blade,
想いを重ねた
our feelings overlap.
祈りは時を越えて
Prayers transcend time.
Your Brave Shine
光ること忘れた
The blue star that forgot how to shine...
青い星が残していく
...leaves behind...
消えない影見てた
...an unerasable shadow I kept watching.
すれ違う赤の軌道
Passing red trajectories...
何も知らない子供のまま
...like a child who knows nothing,
明けない夜を彷徨っていた
I wandered through the endless night.
なくせないものを
The weakness of losing...
なくした弱さ
...what cannot be lost,
何も信じられなくなる脆さ
and the fragility of losing faith in everything.
立てなくなっても
Even if I can no longer stand,
運命は進む
fate moves forward.
夜明けを灯す
Lighting up the dawn
Break down
崩れ落ちてゆく星座が
The crumbling constellations
傷つけ合う夜
Nights where we hurt each other
You're breaking dawn
交わした言葉の中に
In the exchanged words
一人を支えた
Supporting one another
確かな夢を添えて
Accompanied by a certain dream
守りたいものを
What I want to protect
守れるのなら
If I can protect it
全て受け入れて
Accepting everything
明日を探す
Searching for tomorrow
夜明けを灯す
Lighting up the dawn
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
If I reach out my hand, there's still
Stay the night
傷だらけの夜
A night full of scars
You save my life
重ねた涙の果てに
At the end of shed tears
光を見つけた
I found the light
祈りは時を超えて
Prayers transcend time
My brave shine...
Happy birthday, Raora! Happy birthday!
Grazie! Thank you!
Shall we introduce ourselves?
Of course, please do!
OK, 自己紹介をお願いします。
Okay, please introduce yourselves.
Self-introductions, OK!
Self-introductions, okay!
こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の…あ、えーっと、オールド先輩の常闇トワです！
Konyappi! I'm Hololive 4th Gen... ah, um, "old senpai" Tokoyami Towa!
オールド先輩！
Old senpai!
トワ先輩！ありがとう！
Towa-senpai! Thank you!
Old senpai, huh? Really?!
ちょっと待って、Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
Wait a minute, Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
What?!
Okay fine, hello 皆さん！Old senpai Mori Calliope です！
Okay fine, hello everyone! I'm old senpai Mori Calliope!
From Hololive English -Myth-! What's up, fellow pink?
Fellow pink! Pink is powerful!
え、トワ様、you're also pink! It is pink!
Eh, Towa-sama, you're also pink! It is pink!
We kind of... different shades of pink, right?
We kind of... have different shades of pink, right?
Yeah, different shades.
The colors are so important in this live, so we must say that this is the pink team, right?
Colors are so important in this live performance, so we must say this is the pink team, right?
Pink team! Pink-purple team!
ピンクパープルチーム、よろしくお願いします！
We're the Pink-Purple Team, nice to meet you!
Yeah!
Nice, wonderful! But you know, the lighting actually when we were singing the song that we just sang a moment ago was blue.
Nice, wonderful! But you know, the lighting when we sang the song a moment ago was actually blue.
Yeah! It was blue! So pretty, right? Look at that.
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents?
What kind of emotion do you think blue represents?
どんな感情？Blue.
What kind of emotion? Blue.
ブルー？ブルーも結構寂しいとか…
Blue? Blue kind of feels lonely or...
ね！ちょっと悲しいみたいなイメージはあるけど、でも綺麗なイメージもあるよ。
Right! It has a slightly sad image, but it also has a pretty image too.
Also beautiful. Sad, lonely, also beautiful.
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? 怖さ。A little scary, right?
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? Scared. A little scary, right?
Mmm.
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? 感情がめっちゃ美しいと思う。
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? I think emotions are super beautiful.
So, positive, negative, either way, I think colors are really beautiful.
I agree with you. And, you know, even if sometimes we have fear and we're scared of doing something, maybe...
Maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know...
怖くても、頑張らないといけないね。
Even if we're scared, we have to do our best.
例えば、singing on stage together, speaking Japanese... It's kind of scary!
For example, singing on stage together, speaking Japanese... It's kind of scary!
You just gotta try your best, throw your fears away.
怖くないよ！
It's not scary!
チャレンジ！How do you overcome when you're so scared?
Challenge yourself! How do you overcome when you're so scared?
We just sang Brave Shine!
Brave Shine! We just sang!
That's such a good song! It's very fitting.
Right, fight your fears! 怖くないね。
Right, fight your fears! It's not scary, right?
勇気持って！Courage! And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Have courage! Courage! And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Yeah, but fears are also part of our life, right? Like, if we don't feel the fear, then how can we overcome?
Like, how can we do... how to say...
I don't know the word, like...
How can we challenge our past self?
How can we challenge ourself and do our best every single day, right?
How can we challenge ourselves and do our best every single day, right?
怖くなかったら、まあ、チャレンジじゃないよね。
If it wasn't scary, well, it wouldn't be a challenge.
うん、確かにね。
Yeah, that's true.
怖かったら、もっと強くなれると思う。You can become stronger if it's scary.
If you're scared, I think you can become stronger. You can become stronger if it's scary.
かっこいいね！
That's so cool!
直訳？ 意味深...
Naora, so deep...
Wow, deep meaning! That's cool.
かっこいいね！
So cool!
Cute and cool, Raora!
No, no, no, no!
You are cool.
Everyone here is cool.
みんなかっこいい！
Everyone is cool!
Seeing pink is very cool.
Pink's a cool color, okay? Hey!
Well, happy birthday to you!
Thank you so much, Calli!
本当におめでとう！
Congratulations!
Happy Birthday!
Thank you for singing Brave Shine with me!
It's a very meaningful song, and...
...I really appreciate to have my big senpais with me!
Thank you so much!
Yeah, of course! Old senpais here with you!
Well, myself and Towa got to get out of here, but Raora, you keep on keepin' on, okay?
Okay! I'll do my best then!
Yeah, and we'll see you guys later, okay?
See you guys later!
Bye everybody!
Peace! Bye-bye!
白い世界の中では
In a white-colored world,
時間が止まっていくような気がした
I felt as if time had stopped.
いつも見せないような表情が
That expression you rarely show,
その距離が少しだけ愛おしかった
and that distance, felt just a little dear.
巻き戻せないと
Knowing we can't turn back time,
はしゃいでいるその横顔
your side profile as you act playful,
抱えていた悩みも
and the worries I carried...
ちっぽけだ
...feel so trivial.
君に染まる視界が
My view dyed in your colors,
かじかんでいく両手が
my hands growing numb...
心から願うよ
I pray from the bottom of my heart,
終わらせたくはないんだと
wishing it would never end.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
In my memories, your figure is always there.
夢のまま
Remaining in a dream,
覚めないまま
without waking up,
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I just can't forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult.
くだらないことばっか
It's filled with trivial things,
それでも楽しかった
but it was fun nonetheless.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
It'd be nice if this present moment continued forever.
なんてさ僕にはにかんでみせるの
You bashfully smiled at me like that,
泣きそうな声で
with a voice on the verge of tears.
新しい世界では
In a new world,
きっと心から笑えているかな
I wonder if you're laughing from the bottom of your heart.
謝りたいな
I want to apologize,
見せる顔なんてないよ
but I don't even have the face to show you.
僕は君の思う未来のどこにもいないようだ
It seems I am nowhere to be found in the future you envision.
逃げ出したくないよ
I don't want to run away,
あの日に戻りたくなるよ
but I make myself want to return to that day.
振り返ってばかりの人生ならば
If life is full of nothing but looking back,
諦めよう
then let's give up.
いたいけな祈りも
Even innocent prayers,
確かめたい気持ちも
and feelings I want to confirm,
今なら言えるだろうか
can I say them now?
終わらせたくはないんだと知る
I realize I don't want this to end.
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it again and again.
景色は儚げに
The scenery feels fleeting,
足元はおぼつかない
my footsteps are unsteady,
気づけば走り出していたんだ
before I realized it, I was running.
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it again and again.
会いたい言葉など
Words like "I want to see you",
見つかるわけでもない
aren't easy to find,
それでもただ信じてみたいから
but even so, I just want to try believing.
思い出の中君の姿
In my memories, your figure...
夢のまま
Remaining in a dream,
覚めないまま
without waking up,
変わらないな
stays unchanged.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
In my memories, your figure is always there.
夢のまま
Remaining in a dream,
覚めないまま
without waking up,
その笑顔が忘れられないや
I just can't forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ
Words don't seem to be enough.
大人になんてなれないよ
I can't even become an adult.
くだらないことばっか
It's filled with trivial things,
それでも楽しかった
but it was fun nonetheless.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
I wish this present could go on forever like this.
今度は僕からあげて見せるの
Next time, I'll be the one to give it to you.
約束しよう
Let us make a promise.
世界は終わりを告げようとしてる
The world is about to announce its end.
誰にももう止められはしない
No one can stop it anymore.
始まる 崩壊の交響曲が鳴り響いて
It begins... The symphony of collapse resounds,
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
and the falling rain is just like the sound of tears.
教えて
Tell me...
支配し支配され人達は
Those who rule and are ruled,
いつかその心に憎しみを
will they one day find hatred in their hearts...
そして愛することを思い出せず
...and without remembering how to love,
争うの？
will they continue to fight?
この歌が聴こえてる
To all living beings
生命ある全ての者よ
who can hear this song,
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
the truth lies within your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when navigating stormy seas,
決して臆することのない強さを
it will give you a strength that never falters...
くれるから
...because it will grant it to you.
けれども進むほど風は強く
Yet, the further we go, the stronger the wind grows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope eventually fades away.
「灯りをよこせ」と奪い合い
Fighting over "Give me the light!",
果てに人は殺し合う
in the end, people kill one another.
涙などとうに枯れて
Tears have long since dried up,
気付いて
Realize now...
その目は互いを認めるため
Those eyes are meant to recognize each other.
その声は想いを伝えるため
That voice is meant to convey your thoughts.
その手は大事な人と繋ぐためにある
Those hands are meant to connect with precious ones.
この歌が聴こえてる
To all the wanderers across the world
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
who can hear this song,
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
hope lies within your heart.
燃え盛る火焔の中でも
Even amidst the raging flames,
決して傷つくことのない強さを
it will give you a strength that can never be harmed...
くれるから
...because it will grant it to you.
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was the thing you tried to protect with those hands
愛する者だったのだろうか
truly the person you loved?
紅く染まったその手を眺めて
Gazing at those hands stained crimson,
やっと自らがしてきた愚かさを
at last realizing your own foolishness...
過ちと認めるその罪を
...acknowledging it as a mistake, that guilt,
とめどなくあふれるその涙を知る
knowing those tears that overflow boundlessly.
この歌が聴こえてる
To all living beings
生命ある全ての者よ
who can hear this song...
真実は
The truth is
あなたの胸の中にある
within your heart.
嵐の海は静まった
The stormy sea has calmed down,
失ったものは数え切れなくとも
even if the things lost are countless.
この歌が聴こえてる
This song can be heard
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
by all the helpless people in the world.
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope is within your heart.
悲しみの夜を越えるとき
When crossing the night of sorrow,
必ずあなたは生きていく強さを
you will surely have the strength to keep on living,
持てるから
because you possess it.
We did it!
We did it, we did it, we did it!
Look at team fluffy tail!
Look, let's show off our tail!
Look, let's show off our tails!
Woah, wait! Wait, wait, wait! Which one's longer?
Mine is longer!
Happy birthday, Raora!
Yay! Thank you for being here!
Look at her! Look at her!
You should introduce yourself first!
Oh, hi! Who are you? Who is this mysterious creature?
I'm a mysterious creature! How many ears?
One, two, three, four!
Four of them! It's four ears!
Aw, cute!
Why aren't you introducing yourself? Stop!
Hello, Chatini! Hi, I'm Gigi Murin!
And I am a four-eared fox...
and self-proclaimed best friend of the birthday girl over here!
Yay!
She loves me very much, doesn't she?
I love her very much!
Yeah, thank you so much for being here to celebrate!
Thank you for having me! It was so nice to dance with you.
I have come here today to bring you...
a lot of passion...
and determination...
that you need to unleash when you're doing your beautiful art!
Every single day!
I will be very passionate from now on!
I need you to unleash it now! I can't wait any longer!
I've been dancing this whole time!
Give me a hug! Give me a touch!
Just unleash it! Unleash the demon!
I have to go now. Thank you so much for watching.
No, not that! Do you know that...
You'll continue my live. Thank you so much, everyone!
I'm gonna leave you!
No, she won't! Don't leave me!
Do you know the dance for the next song?
It's gonna be very fun. You should...
You want me to join?
Yeah, no, you have to do the live now!
I have to do it live now?
Are you ready? All right, I'm ready!
Okay, show us! You talked about... Oh!
Yes!
Unleash the determination! Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
And now, birthday girl time!
Woah, woah, woah, woah, woah!
Hey!
You can't see that!
Did you see that? 'Cause I saw it!
It's set from the stage!
You saw everything, you don't have to see anything else!
Oh god, you're so violent. That's good!
The determination is coming out!
My passion!
I'm at maximum. Relax.
I can't do that! Come here, Grandma.
Look at her. She wants to talk.
She definitely wants to talk.
What do I want to talk about?
I said, you want to talk.
Who called me Grandma? How freaking dare you!
Look at yourself! All these moves and pull outs...
all the crazy dance.
Oh, it was such a tough dance, was it?
Oh, it was so hard!
She's gonna treat me for dinner to celebrate!
Hey, it's my birthday! You should treat me for dinner!
What are you gonna get for me?
What are you gonna get for me? Good point here.
Oh yeah, because you guys know...
Now get close to the camera! No, this is fine.
I am so... I am so... When I'm done...
I'm gonna give you $10.
Absolutely not!
Yeah, thank you!
That hasn't happened!
Thank you! Thank you, thank you!
It's over!
You know my data for the payment, okay?
Hey, hey, come back!
I don't wanna send you money anymore!
Ah yeah, you got to.
You owe me 40 pounds already! Friend taxes, okay?
She's so in debt with me and she... This is really bad of you!
It's my birthday, I decide what I want and I decide everything, and...
If I want $10, you're gonna give me $10!
What should I do? What should I do, the drama?
Chat, please tell her! Chat, tell her to give me $10!
You look so desperate! You really want this money?
I want it... Fine!
Here it is. Just buy yourself some candy and shit!
I'm over it! I'm so done! Live on stream!
Oh my god, it's over.
The mortgage... oh the car... oh the insurance...
It's okay.
It's okay, let's not talk about negative things now. 'Cause today, it's my birthday, we gotta celebrate!
But did you bring cake for us?
Yes.
Where is it?
Actually...
The cake?
I'm waiting!
Ah, you know, I can't tell you now...
Cake, cake, cake, cake, cake... It's in the other room!
Cake! Hey, don't touch my tail!
Hey, hey, I grabbed your tail!
Come here! Come here! No!
It's kind of easy to get, it's very long.
Listen, listen, you need to walk... need to run away faster!
If you want me to not grab your tail!
Oh, you don't want to? Then I'll grab yours.
Here it comes!
It's a tie! It's a tie!
Taking a bite!
Manager-san! What can manager-san do now?
And she's not gonna be happy with this!
You know what? I'm gonna go and talk to your manager by myself!
No, you cannot talk to my manager! I'll talk to my manager!
I'm so done! I'm done!
No, you're not... Okay, actually, we're done.
That was actually a great workout. We really did deserve cake after all.
Ah, we deserve cake after all, isn't it?
What's your favorite flavor?
My favorite flavor is... Ricotta!
Okay, we have to go now! We have to go!
There's more to come, there's so much more! She has so many surprises for you!
You were the surprise!
Am I? No, am I not known?
But I have more surprises!
She does! She does! She does!
So thank you so much, Ririka!
Yippee! Thank you for having me!
Pink creatura! Pink creatura!
Pink creature! Pink creature!
Grey creatura!
Grey creature!
Oh, yes. You should put some colors on.
Oh, I bought some new glasses, they are nice and red, you should see them. I'll show you sometime soon.
Yippee! Nice to see you!
More songs! More songs to come!
Happy birthday! Yeah, thank you Ririka!
Happy birthday! Okay then, ta-ta!
Bye-bye! Bye!
Bye! Get out of here!
言って。
Say it.
あのね、
You know,
私　実は気付いてるの
I've actually noticed it.
ほら、君が言ったこと
Look, what you said.
あまり考えないと想えなくて
I couldn't help but think about it,
忘れてたんだけど
even though I tried to forget.
盲目的に　盲動的に　妄想的に生きて
Living blindly, impulsively, and delusionally,
衝動的な　焦燥的な　消極的なままじゃ駄目だったんだ
it was no good remaining impulsive, impatient, and passive.
きっと人生最後の日をお前に似合うのだろう
Surely, the last day of my life would suit you.
全部 全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
Even if it's regrettable that I couldn't say everything,
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないこと
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, the fact that you're not here...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more...
ちゃんと言って
Tell me properly.
あのね 空が青いのってどうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
Hey, how should I convey that the sky is blue?
夜の雲が高いのってどうすれば君もわかるんだろう
How can I make you understand that the night clouds are high?
言って
Tell me.
あのね 私実は分かってるの もう君が逝ったこと
Hey, to be honest, I actually know that you're already gone.
あのね 分からず屋って言うんだろうね 忘れたいんだけど
Hey, you'd probably call me stubborn, wouldn't you? Even though I want to forget...
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
Tell me more clearly.
忘れないようメモにしてよ
Write it down so I won't forget.
明日10時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet up at the train platform at 10 tomorrow.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Even if peonies scatter, they're still flowers.
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even if summer passes, remembrance is poignant.
口に出して
Say it out loud.
声に出して
Voice it out.
君が言って
You tell me.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And if I can see you on the last day of my life...
きっと人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
Surely, even on the last day of my life, I will sing of love.
全部全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
Because you'll tell me none of it was in vain.
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことがまだ信じられないけど
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, I still can't believe you won't be here, but...
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more...
君が
You...
もっと もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more, more...
ちゃんと言って
Tell me properly.
Thank you so much for being here, Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai!
I can't believe we sang together! It was so fun!
Yeah! Thank you! Thank you!
次のゲストは、ミオ先輩とおかゆ先輩です！
Our next guests are Mio-senpai and Okayu-senpai!
Raora, Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Happy Birthday! Thank you!
Thank you! 来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！
Our pleasure!
Mind introducing yourselves one more time? Let's go! 紹介、お願いします！
Mind introducing yourselves one more time? Let's go! Please introduce yourselves!
オッケー！ ウチ、ウチ、ウチだよ！ 大神ミオだよ！ ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオでーす！
Okay! It's me, me, me! I'm Ookami Mio! I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
ああ、可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
そしてー！
And next!
はーい！ もぐもぐー？ おかゆー！ ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆでーす！
Hi! Mogu mogu~? Okayu! I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
もぐもぐ！ お願いします！
Mogu mogu! Welcome!
もぐもぐ... もぐもぐ... Yummy, yummy!
Mogu mogu... Mogu mogu... Yummy, yummy!
Thank you so much! ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you very much!
あ、よ、よし！ いくぞー！ えーっと、ミオズ... イングリッシュ... チャレンジ！
Ah, al-right! Here we go! Umm, Mio's English Challenge!
The glow lighting in the concert was beautiful, wasn't it?
You're... you're... you're really beautiful!
ええと、おかゆズ・イングリッシュ・チャレンジ！
Well then, Okayu's English Challenge!
Uh, cyan symbolizes sincerity and self-acceptance.
And you don't have to try to be strong or try to be perfect.
That's right! Just accept yourself as you are, and go with the flow, and you'll be fine.
Can I be strong? Strong cat! I wanna be a strong big cat!
Big cat! Yeah! Raora strong cat! Raora strong cat!
Thank you, senpais, for your nice words!
Thank you! 心に響きました！
Thank you! It touched my heart!
よかった〜！ よかった、よかった！
I'm so glad! I'm glad, I'm glad!
And from here, I've got some exciting news for you guys! It's about Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
So please, senpai, help me out, okay?
お手伝いします！ 任せて！
We'll help you out! Leave it to us!
Okay! So, Raora Panthera 誕生日記念 2026!
Okay! So, Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
グッズの録画…録画？グッズ販売！
Merchandise recording... recording? Merchandise sales!
Okay, okay! Let's go, let's go! Guys, take a look here!
こちらどうぞー！
Here you go!
うわー！ 可愛いねー！
Wow! So cute!
So good! Look at this illustration, do you like it?
うわ、すごい可愛い！ ね、可愛いよ！
Woah, super cute! Yeah, so cute!
The illustration was drawn by Komiya-sensei! Thank you so much for making this beautiful art! I'm so happy!
古宮先生に描いてもらったみたいです！ ライブのラオーラをテーマに描いてもらったみたいですね！
It seems it was drawn by Komiya-sensei! It looks like it was drawn with Live Raora as the theme!
Okay, so let's take a closer look at the details. First up... this one!
Long-sleeved t-shirt!
ロンTだ！ ロンT！
A long-sleeved t-shirt! Long T!
And it features a multi-logo on the back, and there is also design on the sleeves, so it's really cool for everyday life!
So check it out!
ね、なんかロゴとかもついててね、いっぱいデザインが凝ってて可愛いね！
Yeah, it has logos and stuff, the design is super detailed and cute!
And next, we have... ta-da!
Body bag! Body bag! Body bag! I like it!
And it's a bag designed for everyday use that'll let you show off your love for...
Big cat! Big cat! Big cat!
ラオーラ推しをアピールできる、普段使いできるバッグになっております！
It's a bag you can use every day that lets you show your support for Raora!
素晴らしい！ 素晴らしい！
Wonderful! Wonderful!
Thank you! Next up is... ta-da!
Crying Chattini!
どうしたの？ チャッティーニ！
What happened, Chattini?
That's what you deserve! That's what you got! Sorry, sorry. That's what you got!
まあまあまあ！
Now, now, now!
The crying Chattini that comes with an amazing pouch! Next, please!
Next, please! Perfect!
You can combine them together! So good!
チャッティーニが洗濯機の中に閉じ込められちゃったみたいです！ 回ってる！ 回ってる！ チャッティーニ！
It looks like Chattini got locked inside a washing machine! It's spinning! It's spinning, Chattini!
ぐるぐる〜！ ぐるぐるされちゃうの？ ぐるぐる〜！
Round and round! It's getting spun around? Round and round!
はい、こちらね、チャッティーニが閉じ込められてるのはぬいぐるみ用のマルチポーチですね！
Yes, here, where Chattini is trapped, is a multi-pouch for plushies!
すごい！ 可愛い！ 可愛い！
Amazing! Cute! Cute!
And next up is... ta-da! Voice pack!
It's gonna be fun to listen to, so please check it out! Thank you, thank you!
はい、ラオーラがね、頑張って収録したボイス、聴いてみてくださいね、皆さんね！
Yes, please listen to the voice pack that Raora worked hard to record, everyone!
お願いします！ お願いしまーす！
Please do! Please do!
And there is also bonus for purchasing all the full set, and here it is!
The limited quantity items are... cheki-style photo with hand-written autograph!
...with a message, sign...
サイン！ サイン！
Sign! Sign!
こちらは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがフルセットについてきます！
This full set includes an instant photo-style card with an authentic signature!
わー！ すごい！
Wow! Amazing!
And Cheki style bro- bromide... English 難しい...
And Cheki style bro- bromide... English is hard...
English 難しかったー！ 難しいー！ 日々進化する English!
English was hard! It's so hard! English evolves every day!
With foil stamped repro... repro... I can't talk anymore! Signature! Woo!
With foil-stamped repro... repro... I can't talk anymore! Signature! Woo!
ちなみにサインは数量限定となっております！
By the way, the signed version is limited in quantity!
はーい！ お願いしまーす！
Okay! Please check it out!
So here's the full set again, so please go check out, everyone! Thank you, thank you!
And that was the merch info for Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026! Thank you so much!
Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai, thank you so much for your support! Thank you so much!
いいえー！ 上手にフォローできてたかなー？ どうかなー？
You're welcome! I wonder if we were able to back you up well? How was it?
Thank you! でもっすごく楽しかったです！ 楽しかったー！ Yes! So happy! 助かったー！ ありがとう！ 嬉しいー！
Thank you! But it was so much fun! It was fun! Yes! So happy! You saved me! Thank you! I'm so happy!
Alright, now that the merch announcement is done, the next song will be the last one! 最後！
Alright, now that the merch announcement is done, the next song will be the last one! The last!
えぇー！？ Last 1 song!? Last song!?
What!? Last 1 song!? Last song!?
Last song! I'm kind of nervous... Please cheer for me, okay, Senpais?
オッケーオッケー！ 頑張れ頑張れラーオラ！ ファイトファイトー！ ありがとうー！
Okay, okay! Good luck, Raora! Fight, fight! Thank you!
じゃあ、バイバイ！ Let's say goodbye! Okay!
Well then, bye-bye! Let's say goodbye! Okay!
バイバ〜イ！ バイバ〜イ！
Bye-bye~! Bye-bye~!
Draw.
[Title: Draw.]
夢のぬくもりと
Dream's warmth and
指先に絵の具の匂い
The scent of paint on my fingertips
湿ったキャンバスの上には
Above the damp canvas
まだ知らない色が息をする
Colors I still don't know are breathing
All the pieces I picked up
Unravel in my own chest
"It's okay," I whisper softly
Saying it back to myself
迷いも震えも
Doubts and tremors
隠さなくていいから
You don't have to hide them
この線の全部が
All of these lines
私へ続く
Continue to me
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outlines
淡く、脆く、煌めいて
Faintly, fragrantly, sparkling
形になってゆくの
Becoming a shape
夜明けの面影に
In the traces of dawn
集めた色を重ね
Layering the collected colors
Draw it slow, draw it true
夜明けの夢現
The waking dream of dawn
微睡に余白の答え
The answer to the margins in my slumber
白いページに色が咲いていく
Colors bloom on the white page
息づいた景色を描き出す
Drawing out the breathing scenery
All the colors I held back
Start to gather in the hush
"It's all right," the first light tells me
Sending warmth into my heart
願いも希望も
Wishes and hopes
隠さなくていいんだよ
You don't have to hide them, you know
ほら、ありのままの
Look, I'll draw myself
私を描く
Just as I am
At last, hold my true colors
ほどけた輪郭も
Even the untangled outlines
そっと、ずっと、重なって 私の形になる
Gently, continuously overlapping, taking my shape
静かな始まりに 目覚めた色を抱いて
In a quiet beginning, embracing the awakened colors
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
Even the blurred outlines
淡く、脆く、煌めいて 形になってゆくの
Faintly, delicately, shimmering, taking shape
夜明けの面影を 集めた色で描く
Painting the trace of dawn with the gathered colors
Draw it slow, draw it true
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of a dream
指先に絵の具の匂い
And the scent of paint on my fingertips
ありふれた朝の先には
Beyond the ordinary morning
まだ知らない色が溢れてる
Colors I don't yet know are overflowing
Ciao!
Ciao, everyone! I'm still here!
I just wanted to say thank you so, so much for watching my first ever birthday live!
I had so much fun, and I hope you had so much fun, too!
I worked really, really hard, and I'm so happy right now.
Thank you, Chatttini! Thank you everyone for watching!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching!
So, I have to go now. Bye-bye!
And remember, big cat means big trouble!
Rao!
Ciao, everyone! I have one last message for you all.
Be sure to check out the MV premiere right after this!
And also, my new original song will be released on all streaming platforms on May 11, midnight
in your local time zone!
So don't miss it out, okay?
Also go check out my merch!
Bye-bye-bye!
Rao!
Bye-bye!
Thank you to all my Chatttini for all the love and support you have always given me! I will keep working hard!!
THIS WAS MY VERY FIRST 3D BIRTHDAY LIVE! and I hope you all had as much fun as I did! RAOOO! TOGETHER FOREVER!!